《闪电侠》上季回顾
Last season, on "The Flash."
融化
Melt.
-冰霜杀手  -消失了
- Killer Frost... - Is gone.
这里显示还有另外一股低温异常
It says there's still another cryogenic anomaly
存在于我的DNA中
in my DNA.
冰霜杀手还在你体内
Killer Frost is still a part of you.
等一下
Hang on.
就在那
See, right there.
冰霜杀手  那时她就是
Killer Frost, she was part of you.
你的一部分
Even then.
怎么可能
How is that possible?
敬闪电小队最新的成员
To the newest member of Team Flash.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
-你是谁  -我是你的女儿  诺拉
- Who are you? - I'm your daughter, Nora.
卫星进入衰减轨道
Sally's in a decaying orbit.
好吧  我们如何阻止一个
Okay, how do we stop something
撞击时间
三分钟
灾难级别
灭绝
将要把我们送回石器时代的东西
that's going to send us back into the Stone Age?
巴里  你得毁掉那颗卫星
Barry, you've got to destroy that satellite.
最后的卫星
That satellite
不只是我把它干掉的
it wasn't just me who took it down.
还有其他极速者
There was another speedster.
从头讲起吧
Okay, let's back up.
我叫诺拉·韦斯特·艾伦
My name is Nora West-Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的女人
the fastest woman alive.
在我的那个时代里  也即三十年后
When I'm from, 30 years from now,
我是中城的守卫者
I'm the guardian of Central City.
同我父亲一样  我也是名极速者
I'm a speedster, just like my dad.
大家叫我XS
People call me XS.
我日日期盼自己能配得上闪电侠的遗泽
Every day, I hope to live up to the legacy of The Flash...
但我还差得远
But I've still got a long way to go.
你说你是我们的女儿
You're saying you're our daughter?
来自未来
From the future?
叫诺拉
Named Nora?
以你母亲的名字命名
After your mother.
有人要续杯吗
Anybody need a refill?
没人  只有我
No? Just me?
西斯科·拉蒙
Cisco Ramon,
总是用笑话缓解紧张气氛
always cutting the tension with a joke.
你知道我们的名字
You know our names?
当然  我认识你们所有人
Of course. I know all of you.
你是凯特琳·斯诺  拉尔夫·德比
You're Caitlin Snow, Ralph Dibny,
乔爸爸  塞西尔妈妈
Papa Joe, Mama Cecile.
小小的詹娜阿姨
Little Auntie Jenna.
她真可爱
She's so cute.
还有沃利叔叔
And Uncle Wally.
你的外号是XS
Uh, and your nickname is XS?
显然不是我起的
Clearly not my doing.
对  这外号是
No, uh, it's a nickname
妈妈你在我小时候给我起的
that you gave me when I was a kid, Mom.
"妈妈"
"Mom"?
你说我干什么都过头[XS]
You said I did everything in excess.
我好像一直都这样
Guess I've always been like that.
用力过头  插手我处理不了的事
Overdoing things, getting in way over my head.
比如  最近
Like, uh, recently.
你犯的这个错误
This mistake that you made?
大错误
Big mistake.
比如
Which was...
昨晚摧毁了尖端科研实验室的卫星
Helping you save the city
来帮助你们拯救中城
by destroying the STAR Labs satellite last night.
你就是另外那个极速者
You were the other speedster?
我就是忍不住
I just couldn't stop myself
不去插手
from getting involved.
但我插手时出了点问题  因为现在
But something happened when I did, because now,
我好像没法加速到打开神速力的水平了
I can't seem to go fast enough to open up the Speed Force.
等等
Par--pardon me.
我们说的是真正的时空穿越吗
Are we talking about actual time travel here?
你是不是刚刚
Do you just like, not pay any attention
压根没听我们的情况简介
when we have our briefings?
你们都没告诉他传奇的事吗
Y'all didn't teach him about the Legends?
没人提过一丁点时空穿越的事
Look, nobody said bubkes about time travel.
拜托  拉尔夫  你吓着孩子了
Come on, Ralph. You're scaring the baby.
对  你吓着孩子了
Yeah, you're scaring the baby.
不  她不是害怕
No, no, she's not scared.
她刚说她饿了
She just said she's hungry.
她说她  乔
She said that she's-- Joe!
我听到她的声音啦
I heard her!
我读到了她的心
I read her mind!
我可能没有失去我的能力
I might not be losing my powers!
太棒了
Awesome.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我知道这非常不可思议
I know how bizarre this must seem,
遇到你们来自未来的成年女儿什么的
meeting your daughter from the future as an adult.
但说真的  我根本没打算这么做
But really, this wasn't my plan at all,
我就是卡在这个时代了
but I'm kind of stuck here now,
而你们是唯一能帮我的人
and you're the only people who can help me.
有人知道该怎么办吗
So...anybody know what to do?
闪 电 侠
第五季
第一集
这真是太奇怪了
This is so, so weird.
我真没法相信那是我们的女儿
Yeah, I mean, I can't believe that's our daughter up there.
-我们遇见过骗子  -巴里
- We have been lied to before. - Barry.
和你一样的黄色闪电  和我一样的紫色闪电
Yellow lightning like yours, purple lightning like mine?
肯定是她
I mean, it's-- it's got to be her.
我们和我们的女儿初次相见  巴里
We're meeting our daughter for the first time, Barry.
要是这是真的
Yeah, well, look. If it is true,
诺拉可能说错话或者做错事
Nora could say the wrong thing or step on the wrong butterfly
引发蝴蝶效应  毁掉整个时间线
and screw up the whole timeline.
她能像马蒂·麦克弗莱一样毁掉她自己的存在
I mean, she could Marty McFly herself out of existence.
《终结者2》
Mm, "Terminator 2," Yeah.
不  那是《回到…》  算了
No, that's "Back to the"-- It doesn't matter.
我们得负责任点
Look, we just need to be responsible, all right?
我们得赶紧想法子把她送回家
I mean, I think we need to find a way to send her home, fast.
巴里  你觉得未来的我们
Barry, don't you think future us taught our daughter
会没教过我们的女儿别干预时间线吗
how not to screw with the timeline?
这极速实验室看着真复古
Wow, this Speed Lab sure is archaic, huh?
你知不知道
La-la-la-la-la, you don't know--
就是
you know what, um...
别谈论未来的事  行吗
Sorry, just--no future talk, all right, please?
好  我也不想破坏时间线
Right, I don't want to wreck the timeline.
诺拉
All right, Nora.
这个是分析我们的血缘的
This is gonna link us up with your biometrics.
这个小发圈一样的玩意
And this little scrunchy doohicky
能分析你和...
is gonna analyze your connection to the, um, uh--
神速力
The Speed Force.
神速力的关系  谢谢
The Speed Force. Thank you.
棒
Great.
我马上回来
I'll be back in a...flash.
结果如何
And what does it say?
她的DNA快速分析显示
A quick analysis of her DNA shows patterns
和你们俩的模式如出一辙
that are similar to both of yours.
我就知道  她是我们的女儿
I knew it. She's our daughter.
那她困在这里的情况呢
What about her being stuck here?
一切都正常
Everything's normal.
她体内肯定有神速力
She definitely has Speed Force in her system.
只是她的速度不够快
She's just not going... fast enough
不足以打开时间传送门
to, uh, open up a time portal, so.
你在乔和塞西尔家喝了多少香槟
How much champagne did you have at Joe and Cecile's?
这是我第一次有机会
This is the first opportunity I have
去消化我和吉普赛分手的事
to process my breakup with Gypsy, okay?
我怎么知道
How was I supposed to know
你未来的女儿会出现
that your future daughter was gonna come show up
毁了我的失恋悲痛
and crash my pity party?
我怎么预料到会发生这种事
How was I supposed to "Ancipitate" that?
糟了  我一小时前就该去中城警局见辛格的
Crap, I was supposed to meet Singh at CCPD an hour ago.
-好  -沃利  能帮我个忙吗
- Okay. - Hey, Wally, can you do me a favor?
你能把这个样本送去给传奇们吗
Can you take the sample to the Legends
看看他们有什么见解
to see if they have any insight?
也许万不得已的时候
And maybe, worst comes to worst,
我们可以用乘波号送她回家
we can take her home on the Waverider?
-知道了  -好
- Yeah, I got it. - All right.
好  我很快就回来
Okay, just-- I'll hurry back.
看着她
Keep an eye on her.
新证件   实验室钥匙
New ID, keys to the lab.
你正式恢复犯罪现场调查员的职位了  艾伦
You are officially reinstated as our CSI tech, Allen.
谢谢你  队长
Thanks, Captain.
还有一件事
Oh, one more thing.
你离职的时候  我们没找人填补你的空缺
We didn't fill your position while you were away,
所以你的实验室里有几件案子在等着你
so there are a few cases waiting for you in your lab.
尽快着手去做
Get to them fast as you can.
欢迎归队  艾伦
Welcome back, Allen.
这叫几件吗
"A few"?
你在查什么案子
What you working on?
-我不...  -你落后太多了
- I don't-- - You are crazy behind.
你不是要留在星城实验室
Hey, so I thought you were gonna stay at STAR Labs,
和你的
with, um...with your...
爱瑞丝  妈妈
Iris-- mom.
你妈妈
Your mom.
你知道我也是一名鉴证专员吧
You know I'm a forensic scientist too?
和你一样是中城大学毕业  平均成绩优异
CCU grad, just like you. 5.6 GPA.
我可以帮你搞定这些
I could help you get through this.
我不知道  这...
Oh, I don't know. I mean, it's--
这个地方的消防局局长说
So the fire marshal at this site says
融化玻璃的裂痕显示有液体催化剂
crazing in the melted glass suggests a liquid accelerant.
任何以石油为基础的家用产品
Mm, any petroleum-based household product
都有可能造成裂痕
could cause crazing.
比如说地板蜡  长绒毯子  甚至气球
Well, like floor wax, or shag rugs, even balloons.
玻璃在表面以下融化
Yeah, the glass melts under the surface,
就像华夫筒裂缝里的冰淇淋一样
like ice cream in the cracks of a waffle cone.
就像在罗德岛欢乐港
Oh, like when you get two scoops
梅森家冰淇淋店的
of cookie dough ice cream with extra sprinkles
双球曲奇饼粒冰激凌
at the Mason Family Ice Cream Shop in...
然后多加一点彩色糖粒
Happy Harbor, Rhode Island.
小时候我爸妈经常带我去
My parents used to take me there when I was a kid.
那是我最爱的甜品
It's my favorite dessert.
我也是
Mine too.
对不起  显然你很擅长做鉴证
Hey, look, I'm sorry, um, you're obviously
但是你不该干涉
good at forensics, but you shouldn't interfere.
干我们这行需要有责任感
I mean, people like us, we need to be responsible.
没错  时间线
Right! Uh, timeline.
时间线
The timeline, yeah.
各单位请注意
All available units,
第十街和尼利街处发生M03
M-0-3 in progress, 10th and Neely.
M03就是超能力者袭击事件
M-0-3, that's a meta attack.
我的战衣都撕破了
Yeah, my suit's all torn up.
我什么也没有
I don't have anything to--
直接从西斯科的衣柜里拿来的
Direct from Cisco's back closet.
红色徽章原版超级战衣的最初设计版
One first-edition red emblem OG super suit.
绝对是闪电迷的最爱
Total fan favorite.
谢谢
Thank you.
我要去处理这案子
Uh, I'm-- I'm gonna handle this.
你就...  不不不
You just-- no, no, no.
你留在这
Uh, you... stay.
-好吗  -好
- Okay? - Okay.
我说真的
Seriously, please.
我要...
Now I'm gonna...
今天走复古路线啊  闪电侠
Going old-school today, Flash?
不过这战衣比我记忆中要更紧身一点
Yeah, it's a little tighter than I remember, though.
你是不是要做点什么
Hey, uh, you might want to do something.
轮到我了  闪电侠
Now it's my turn, Flash.
路霸  棒呆了
Gridlock? Schway!
-你来干什么  -不是
- What are you doing? - No, no.
我只是想要
I just-- I just wanted--
爽
Nice.
完了  你们生我的气了
Oh, grife. You're mad at me.
不  诺拉  我们没有  我们只是
No, Nora, we're not. We're just--
请别说大失所望
Please don't say "Disappointed."
那样更糟
That's so much worse.
我只是觉得那没什么大不了的
I mean, I just didn't think it was a big deal.
只是路霸而已
It was only Gridlock.
路霸
Oh, Gridlock, huh?
天呐  未来人起名字可真蹩脚
Boy, the future's got some great names.
这光真刺眼
This lighting!
你怎么知道他是谁
How did you know who he is?
闪电侠博物馆
Flash Museum.
你刚才说
Did you say...
-闪电侠博物馆  -嗯
- "Flash Museum"? - Yeah.
里面所有的反派和战斗是按时间顺序来排列的
It has all the villains and battles in chronological order.
我全部都研究过
I've studied everything.
那你知道这个人的真名吗
So you know this guy's real name?
馆长迈尔斯先生
Mr. Myles, the curator,
因为法律的原因  他把所有人名都删除了
he scrubbed all the names for legal reasons.
但这真的不重要
But it really shouldn't matter.
反正路霸只出现一次
I mean, Gridlock was a one-and-done.
你们一次就打赢他了
You guys beat him in one try,
或者只是应该是这样
or at least... you were supposed to.
现在因为我  他逃走了
Ugh, now, because of me, he's on the run,
时间线又全都打乱了  我
and the timeline's all messed up again, and I--
诺拉  听着
Nora, hey, look, look.
我犯过比这次时间穿越更大的错误
I've made way bigger mistakes than this time traveling.
我们会抓到他的  你不用担心
We'll get this guy-- you don't need to worry about that--
但你在这待得越久  改变的事可能就会更多
but the longer you stay here, the more things might change.
我们要送你回家
We need to get you home.
但是我达不到回家的速度
But I can't go fast enough to get home.
那用超光速粒子吸收增强器如何
What about the tachyon absorption enhancer?
就是斯旺用来增加他速度的那个
The one that Thawne used to increase his speed?
如果我们给它充上电
Ooh, and if we charge it up,
我就可以  加速她细胞内的神速力
we could uh, boost the Speed Force in her cells,
就像是...
like some kind of, um...
某种增强她细胞内神速力的东西
thing that boosts Speed Force in cells.
对对  这是个好办法
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. That's a good idea.
好  找到路霸
Let's--okay, finding Gridlock
把诺拉送回家应该是我们的首要任务
and getting Nora home need to be our priorities.
不不不  不行不行不行
No, no, no. Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop.
-等下  -太吵了
- Wait. - Loud!
好了  这个应该是我们的首要任务
Okay, so--but this needs to be our priority.
我知道你们在这类时间旅行的事上
Now, I realize that you're all way ahead of me
比我了解的多  但各位
in this time-travel business, but guys,
我想我发现了些什么
I think I just discovered something.
所以  如果诺拉可以穿越时间
So if--if Nora can time travel,
这就意味着她可以创造新的时间线  对吧
that means she can create new timelines, right?
新时间线意味着并行时间线会存在
New timelines means that parallel timelines can exist.
所以各位
So, guys,
我认为可能有很多不同宇宙同时存在
I think that a whole other universe could exist.
我知道  我知道
I know, I know, I know.
这听起来很疯狂  但试想一下
It sounds crazy, but think about it.
可能有一个地球上  我们都是坏人
There could be an Earth where we're all bad guys,
或者另一个地球上没有饥荒
or another Earth where there's no world hunger,
或者  或者另一个地球上
or--or another Earth where--
他们从来没有拍最后那部《夺宝奇兵》
where they never made that last "Indiana Jones" Movie.
想想这些可能性吧
Think of the possibilities.
就像是某种多样宇宙
It's like some kind of a manyverse.
你们是都知道有多样宇宙存在了吧
And everybody knows about the manyverse.
多元宇宙  你也知道的  拉尔夫
Multiverse, and so do you, Ralph.
穿越者  吉普赛  哈里
Breacher? Gypsy? Harry?
你觉得我们说哈里来自地球二的时候
What did you think we meant when we said
我们在说什么
Harry was from Earth-2?
是说他也是从地球来的
That he is from Earth "Also."
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
你们真的需要做个欢迎手册
You guys really need to make, like, a welcome pamphlet,
至少弄个PPT什么的
or at least a Powerpoint or something.
拉尔夫  伙计
Hey, Ralph, buddy?
咱们能不能别思考时间旅行了  好吗
Can we get off time travel, maybe, please?
咱们先专注找到路霸  行吗
Let's focus on finding Gridlock, all right?
谢谢
Thank you.
我去趟中城警局
I'm gonna go to CCPD,
看看能不能找到些线索
see what I can dig up.
好  我和诺拉呆在一起
Okay, I'll stay with Nora.
-咱们要确保  -我知道
- Let's just make sure- - I know.
保护时间线
Protect the timeline.
你渴吗
You thirsty?
我的拿铁  你的无咖啡因"闪电侠"
Okay, latte for me, and a decaf Flash for you.
爸爸的闪电比闪电小子的酷多了
Dad's lightning bolt is way cooler than Lightning Lad's.
你觉得他很快就能回来吗
And do you think he's gonna be back soon?
你知道你爸爸的
Well, you know your dad.
只要一有麻烦  他就一定要跑去解决
Whenever there's a problem, he's gotta run off and fix it.
不过也好
But, you know,
这给了我们机会沟通
this gives us a chance to connect.
你不怕像他一样把事情搞砸吗
You're not worried about messing things up, like he is?
我  我只是...
I--well, I just, I...
想要多了解你一些
want to get to know you a little.
这样如何
How about this?
我会问你一个
I will ask you questions
关于你生活的问题  如果我说对了
about your life, and if I'm right,
你就眨眼两次
you just blink twice.
眨眼从来没有破坏过时间线  对吧
I mean, blinking never broke the timeline, right?
好吧  如果你真想这样的话
Okay, yeah, I mean, if you really want to.
我觉得会很有趣
Yeah, I think it'll be really fun.
好了  让我看看
Okay, um, so let's see.
你是某个报社的记者
You are a reporter for a newspaper
你们只在图片分享网站报道
that you can only read on Instagram.
好吧  你是个警察
Um, okay, you--you are a cop.
你是犯罪现场调查员
You're a--a CSI?
你是个犯罪现场调查员
You're a CSI.
就和你爸爸一样
Just like your dad.
好吧  那你和我呢
Okay, well, what about you and I?
我们会不会每周日一起聚餐
Do we--do we, like, have dinner every Sunday?
我们在电话上聊天吗
Do we talk on the phone?
我们还会去吉特斯一起喝咖啡吗
Do we still get coffee at Jitters?
那是眨眼了吗
Uh... Was that a blink?
不是  我只是眼睛里进东西了
Uh, no, I just-I have something in my eye.
在我的时代吉斯特299块钱一杯
You know, a coffee in my time at Jitters is $43 a cup.
这也是我喜欢现在的一个点
That's one thing I really like about now.
2018年相当得劲
2018 is way schway.
"得劲"
"Schway"? Oh.
这可能是未来的流行语
Yeah, I guess it's a future thing.
不是  "得劲"
Oh--oh, no. Oh, "Schway."
我当然知道得劲的意思
No, I know, I'm hip. I know what schway means.
就像是  我很得劲  你也得劲
Like, I'm schway, you're schway.
我们超得劲  宝贝
We're--we're schway, baby.
蠢死了
Stupid.
你觉得凯瑟琳和西斯科需要帮助吗
Do you think maybe Caitlin and Cisco need any help?
真不敢相信我带着的超光粒子增强器
I can't believe I'm wearing the same tachyon enhancer
是我爸第一次见超女时候用的
my dad used to meet Supergirl for the first time.
都弄好了
All set.
等下  第二代去哪了
Wait, what happened to the second version?
更小那一版  放在我爸爸第二套战服的
The smaller one that was inside the emblem
闪电标志里那个
of my dad's second suit?
如果他戴上那个  他就可以吸收超光粒子
Um, if he wore that one, he could harness tachyons
然后和我共享
and share them with me.
脑残粉  冷静下
Hey, fangirl, relax.
我们知道这些
We know.
这些衣服都能缩小吗
Did all these suits shrink?
还有为什么闻起来这么糟糕
And why does it smell so bad?
因为那件是你用来
Because it's the one you used
和鲨鱼王对决时穿的
when you swam against King Shark.
是啊  是啊
Oh, yeah, yeah.
闪电侠
Flash!
极速要你死
Zoom wants you dead!
我知道鲨鱼王严格来说是个坏人
I know King Shark is technically a bad guy,
但你等着瞧吧
but you should see-just wait.
当他和古鲁德对战时...
When he fights Grodd, it's-Um!
剧透了啊
Spoiler alert.
咱们该开始了  真的...
We should get going, actually, let's--
好了
Right.
那这就是道别了
Then this is goodbye.
最起码是从你们的角度来看
From your guys' perspectives, at least.
我会在1分27秒后再见到你们
I'll see you again in a minute and 27 seconds,
但你们再见到我时  我还只是个婴儿
but when you see me again, I'll be a baby.
一路顺风  诺拉
Get home safe, Nora.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry
没能多陪陪你
we didn't get to spend more time together.
没关系  老妈
Oh, it's fine, Mom.
我们将相伴一生
We spend our whole lives together.
好了
All right.
他们已经走了吗
Did they already leave?
是啊  怎么了
Yeah, why? What's up?
我们得阻止他们
We have to stop them.
抱歉我来晚了
I'm sorry I was too late.
找到传奇们的位置可花了我不少时间
It took me a while to find where the Legends were.
准确说是他们所处的时空
Well, when they were.
我们让吉迪恩
But we got their Gideon
扫描了诺拉的血样
to scan Nora's blood sample.
-她发现了什么  -负超光子
- What'd she find? - Negative tachyons.
负超光子
Negative tachyons?
那是什么  与加速相反会让你减速吗
So, what, instead of speeding you up, they slow you down?
对
Yeah.
该死  我开玩笑的
Oh, damn, I was just joking.
还真是这样
That's a real thing?
艾娃和她的团队在时间调查局
Yeah, Ava and her team at the Time Bureau
接触过负超光子  但没人知道
have encountered them before, but no one knows
它们从哪来  如何产生
where they come from or how they're generated.
就像是时空连续体的暗物质
Like dark matter for the space time continuum.
没错  现在正侵蚀着诺拉的身体
Exactly, and they're saturating Nora's body
阻止她进入神速力
and keeping her from entering the Speed Force.
乘波号呢  传奇们能把她带走吗
What about the Waverider? Can the Legends take her back?
如果乘波号在时空穿梭时
If negative tachyons come anywhere near
接触到负超光子
the Rider's time drives,
整艘船都将支离破碎
uh, the reaction will vaporize the ship.
总会有办法摆脱这些负超光子  对吧
Well, there's got to be a way to get rid of them, right?
虽然不知道怎么摆脱负超光子
I mean, I don't know about getting rid of them,
但也许可以通过抵消
but maybe we can offset
超光速粒子吸收增强器
the tachyon absorption enhancer
使接触时的反应失效
to negate the reaction somehow.
-新的超能力者被发现时  -伙计们
- A new meta was last seen... - Hey, guys.
偷盗珠宝后为逃脱追捕
Jumping off a building in order to
而跳下了大楼
evade capture after stealing jewels...
我们怎么没发现到他
How did we miss this?
一定是迪沃送来的临别饯礼
I guess this is a parting gift from DeVoe.
失去了尖端科研实验室卫星
Without our STAR Labs satellite,
意味着无法洞悉外界  没有暗物质扫描仪
we've lost our eyes, our ears, our dark matter scanner,
没有面部识别软件  这样只能
our facial recognition-- I mean, we're always
永远比那些超能力者晚一步行动
gonna be one step behind these metas now.
这边交给我吧
I'll work on this.
你们去帮拉尔夫
Why don't you guys go help Ralph
调查路霸的犯罪现场
with the Gridlock crime scene, okay?
我来帮忙
I can come help.
不用了  只是
Please, no, just--we just
不能让情况变得更糟  知道吗
can't let this get any worse, all right?
好好休息吧
Just relax, okay?
调查进展得如何
How's your investigation going?
实在是有点说不通
Uh, it just doesn't really add up.
如果艾迪想让斯旺彻底消失
I mean, if Eddie wanted to erase Thawne from existence,
那他干嘛不去做个结扎手术
why didn't he just have a vasectomy?
他们什么都不说
Right, uh, nobody's talking.
他们也许是害怕
Probably because they're afraid
路霸会伤害他们
Gridlock will attack them.
要是冰霜杀手在的话
Right, but maybe if I had Killer Frost at my side,
他们也许会愿意
people would be a little more willing
向我们透露些消息
to tell us what they know.
拉尔夫  迪沃占据你身体那一晚
Ralph, Killer Frost has been gone
冰霜杀手就已经消失了
since the night that DeVoe took over your body.
天啊  怎么什么事都不告诉我
Jeez Louise, no one tells me anything.
-她永远不会回来了  -希望不是吧
- Is she gone for good? - I hope not.
我已经想尽一切办法
But I've tried everything I can think of
让她重新出现
to get her to reappear.
你没有其他线索了吗
You don't have any other leads?
西斯科用震波发现了
Cisco vibed me back to when
年轻时的我和冰霜杀手
Killer Frost and I were younger.
你从小就是超能力者了
You've been a meta since you were a kid?
-应该是的  -怎么会
- I guess so. - How?
-我也不知道  -还看到什么了
- I have no idea. - Did you see anything else?
-还看到了我爸爸  -那还是有收获的
- Just that my dad was there. - Well, that's something.
但我老爸已经死了很多年了
Except my dad's been dead for years.
不说这些没意义的了
But none of this matters right now.
我们还有更重要的事要做
We have much more pressing things to deal with.
来看看这个
Hey, come look at this.
有请路霸
I present Gridlock.
三幕结构的谜题
A mystery in three acts.
请注意暗物质水平
Please note the dark matter levels.
第一幕  巴里出现前路霸袭击了警察
Act One, Gridlock attacks the cops before Barry shows up.
像他这么庞大的人
Okay, but these dark matter levels
这样的暗物质水平很正常
are perfectly normal for a man of his size.
直到第二幕
Until Act Two.
他挨了巴里的光速拳
He gets lightning punched by Barry.
他的暗物质含量迅速攀升
His dark matter levels increased.
接下来是第三也就是最后一幕
Which brings us to our third and final act...
路霸反击
Gridlock hits back.
又增加了
Even higher.
这  这怎么可能
How--how is that possible?
是不可能  除非路霸每次受到攻击
It isn't, unless every time Gridlock got hit,
他的细胞都吸收了动能
his cells absorbed the kinetic energy.
这样会增加他的暗物质指数
That would increase his dark matter quotient,
从而增加他的力量
thereby increasing his powers.
如果真是这样  只要他受到攻击
If this is true, then whatever movement he's exposed to--
他就会变得越来越强大
The stronger he's gonna get.
如果路霸不断变强  最终将会势不可挡
So, if Gridlock keeps moving, he becomes unstoppable.
有头绪了吗
So, figure it out yet?
不论这些负超光子是什么
Whatever these negative tachyons are,
都感觉是科幻小说里虚构的
it feels a lot more like science fiction
而不属于真正的科学
than actual science.
我关心的不是科学
I wasn't asking about the science.
而是科学家
I was asking about the scientist.
你和诺拉  你们有着强大的联系
You and Nora, you guys have such a strong connection.
这是与生俱来的
I mean, it's... it's effortless.
你又为何执意要送她回去
So why are you so intent on sending her back?
你到底想说什么
I mean, what do you mean?
首先  她总是把未来的生活挂在嘴边
First of all, she can't stop talking about the future.
你也知道她的出现影响了时间线
But--I mean, you know the danger that her being here
是非常危险的
poses to the timeline.
对我知道  但我也很了解你  巴里
Yeah, I do, but I also know you, Barry.
听着
Look.
是你穿越回过去
You're the guy that went back in time
-带回了死前的史纳特  -我知道
- to borrow Snart before he died. - I know.
同样的你穿越到了2020年
You're also the same guy that travelled to 2020
搞清了萨维塔是谁
to figure out who Savitar was,
还去2015年和威尔斯训练
and 2015 to train with Wells.
为了救我  你改变了命运
You changed fate to save my life.
现在我们的女儿就在我们面前
So, now that our daughter is here in front of us,
向我们寻求帮助  你却想让我相信
asking for our help, you expect me to believe
你在担心时间线吗
that you're worried about the timeline?
诺拉不应该在这里
Nora shouldn't be here.
我...
Look, I'm--
-我总是想要一个家庭  -我知道
- I've always wanted a family. - I know.
我们结婚的时候
You know, and when we got married,
我就知道  有一天我们会决定要孩子
I knew that one day, we'd decide to have a baby.
我们会努力尝试  然后你会怀孕
We would try, and you'd get pregnant.
我会看到超声波图  听她的第一次心跳
I'd be there for the sonogram, I'd hear her first heartbeat,
她会来到这个世界上
and then she'd come.
我们带她回家  看她的第一次笑
And we'd take her home, see her first smile,
第一颗牙  第一次我读书给她听
her first tooth, the first time I read to her.
第一次迈步  第一次跑起来
Her first steps. The first time she ran.
但是她现在在这里  你不觉得
But her being here now, don't you feel like
我们错过了这所有的第一次吗
we missed all those firsts?
我们跳过了这所有美好的事情
That we skipped all the good stuff?
亲爱的  我们还是会有这些第一次的
Baby, we will still have all of those firsts.
只不过换了顺序
Just not in that order.
但是我的整个生活都一直是乱的
But my whole life's been out of order.
这些能力  时间旅行
These powers, time travel--
就因为这些我妈妈才被杀害
that's the reason my mom was killed,
让我爸久蹲监狱  缺席我的成长
why I grew up with my dad in prison.
他们错过了很多第一次  甚至是我们的婚礼
They missed so many firsts. They missed our wedding.
我知道
I know.
我不知道  我只是觉得等我们有孩子的时候
I don't know, I just thought that when it was our turn to have a kid,
生活能让我们把这些小事
that life would let us have this one little thing
过得正常一点
the normal way.
就一次
Just once.
但是我们已经失去这个机会了
But we lost that chance.
不  我们并不会因为她在这里就失去什么
No, we're not losing anything by having her here now.
我们只是得到了额外的东西  巴里
We're only gaining something extra, Barry.
如果我们解决了这件事情
And look, if we figure this out,
等我们真正有了孩子的时候
I mean, by the time we do have a baby,
我们会成为最好的父母
we are gonna be the best parents ever.
-或许你是对的  -我知道我是对的
- Maybe you're right. - I know I'm right.
你会把硬币放在她的枕头底下
You're gonna be there to put that quarter under her pillow,
你会
and you're gonna be there
开车送她第一天上学
to drive her to her first day of school,
你会为她的第一次跑步喝彩
and you're gonna be there to cheer on her first run.
我们会有这所有的第一次
And we are gonna have all of those firsts.
我保证
I promise.
再想一想
And think about it.
我们的孩子现在可以违抗物理学定律
We have a kid who defied the laws of physics
和她的父母一起消遣
to hang out with her parents.
这可是非常  非常的得劲了
I mean, that's pretty-- that's pretty schway.
是啊  她这么热切  就好像她是那个
Yeah, as eager as she is, you'd think that she's the one
成长期间父亲在...
that grew up with a parent in...
怎么了
What's wrong?
没事  没事
Nothing. Um, nothing.
我  我去去就回
I'm--I'm gonna be right back.
诺拉
Nora.
未来的我出什么事了
What happens to me in the future?
你说你一生都是和你妈一起过的
You said that you spend your whole life with your mom,
但是你没说和我也一样
but you didn't say the same for me.
我的扑克脸摆得不好  是吧
My poker face is that bad, huh?
我需要知道
I need to know.
闪电侠失踪  消失于危机之中
消失了多久
How long?
25年后  闪电侠仍未出现
你再也没有回来
You never come back.
那个时候你多大了
How old were you when it happened?
我在你消失的前几年出生
I was born, um, a few years before you vanished,
但是我一点都不记得你了
but I don't have any memories of you.
所以那场婚礼
So the wedding was...
差不多是我第一次见到你
Was pretty much the first time I met you.
我想像过太多不同的话要对你说
I'd imagined so many different things to say to you.
还是不敢相信我居然说的是"记得说我愿意"
Still can't believe I went with "Remember to say 'I do.'"
事情总是不能像你计划的那样发展
I guess things don't always go the way you plan them.
你并不是被困在这了  对吗
You're not stuck here, are you?
我在博物馆档案里发现的
I found it in the museum archive.
负超光子  按需使用
Negative tachyons, harnessed on demand.
我真应该好好练习下扑克脸
Really should work on that poker face, I guess.
这没必要保密的
This didn't have to be a secret.
你为什么不告诉我们
Why did you keep this from us?
因为一旦你知道我可以回家
Because if you knew I could have gone home,
你就会在我
you would have sent me back
踏进爷爷家门的那一刻就把我送回去
the second I walked into Grandpa's house.
就像你说的  爸爸
I mean, it's like you said, Dad.
极速者需要有责任感
Speedsters have to be responsible.
但是  我没责任感  是不是
But--but I'm not responsible, am I?
我只是自私而已
I'm...just selfish
而且一点都当不好极速者
and really, really bad at being a speedster.
诺拉  你不是不好
Nora, you're not bad.
我可以做一些很酷的事情  你知道吗
I mean, I can do some cool things, you know?
有时候我跑得很快  能够扭转一点点时间
Sometimes, I run so fast, I reverse time a bit,
但是我做不到你能做的事情
but I can't do the things you can.
我甚至还不知道该怎么穿墙
I don't even know how to phase yet.
从博物馆能学到的太少了
Guess there's only so much you can learn from a museum.
妈妈后来怎样了
What about your mom?
她在我身边
Yeah, I--she's around, you know?
就只有我和她
It's just, uh-- just me and her.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
我不应该说谎
I shouldn't have lied.
我只是太想见到你了
I just wanted to see you so badly
想和你在一起过一天
and spend a day with you.
第一次一起跑一跑
Go for a run for the first time together.
我错过了你所有的第一次
I missed all your firsts.
我担心过弄糟你的童年
I was so worried about screwing up your childhood
弄糟我们的家庭  但是
and screwing up our family, but...
结果我都不在其中
I'm not even there.
巴里  我们需要你到表层来
Barry, we need you in the Cortex.
是关于路霸的事
It's about Gridlock.
我没事
I-- - I'm fine.
你需要去补救我的烂摊子  然后我就能回家了
you need to go fix my mess, and then I can go home.
我扫描了犯罪现场照片  找到了匹配的人
I scanned the crime scene photos and got a match.
这不是朗第一次犯事
This is not Lang's first rodeo.
威廉·朗
中城警局因为劫车给他下了逮捕令
CCPD put out a warrant for him for carjacking.
他杀了车里的全部乘务员
He killed the whole crew inside.
他现在又在吸收动能了吗
And now he absorbs kinetic energy?
只有在你打他的时候  他才会变强
He only gets stronger if you punch him,
你开枪打他  你把他扔进车流
you shoot him, you throw him into traffic.
都只会让交通状况更差
Which could only make the traffic worse.
我可不想被困在路上
God, I'd hate to be stuck in that gridlock.
路霸  路霸
Gridlock... Gridlock...
是我给他取的这个名字
I came up with the name.
我真是幸运的傻子
I am fortune's fool.
所以没有卫星的话我们要怎么找到这个人
So how do we find this guy without Sally the satellite?
黑进一部手机不需要卫星
We don't need a satellite to hack a cell phone.
如果我们想定位他的手机  我们会发现它
And if we want to find his cell phone, we'll find it...
在机场
By the airport?
找到了  他在一架刚刚起飞的飞机上
Got it, 'cause he's on a plane that just took off.
中城航空  航班号5201
Central City Air, flight number 5201.
他为什么要上飞机
Why would he get on a plane?
因为他想让飞机坠毁
Because he's gonna crash it.
飞机目前巡航高度一万米
We are currently cruising at 34,000 feet.
预计将平稳降落
We anticipate a smooth landing,
请坐在座位上
so sit back and enjoy...
打扰一下  先生
Excuse me, sir.
请系好安全带
If you could please fasten your seatbelt
等我们达到巡航高度
until we reach cruising altitude
机长熄灭安全带指示灯之后再解开
and the captain turns off the seatbelt sign.
你要给那个箱子也系上安全带吗
Are you gonna buckle that thing in too?
它自己占了一个座位  一定很贵重
Well, it must be something priceless to get its own seat.
可能是珠宝
Jewels, maybe.
飞机的一个引擎失灵了
The plane just lost an engine.
它会在市中心坠毁
It's headed for downtown.
碰撞航向警告
如果路霸破坏另一个引擎
If Gridlock takes out the other engine,
飞行员将无法绕开大楼
the pilot won't be able to avoid the buildings.
成千上万的人会死
Thousands of people will die.
你可以让飞机穿过大楼
Not if you phase the plane through the buildings.
我看到过你的新闻
I read about you doing the same thing
你在未来和暴民党战斗时对一架飞机这样做了
to a plane in the future when you were fighting Mob Rule.
你们两个能做到吗
Can you two do that?
一架飞机
A plane?
不  我认为不能
No-- I mean, no, I don't think so.
我觉得它太大了
I mean, I think it's too big.
我们三个
The three of us.
我们三个人一起也许能做到
I mean, the three of us might be able to do it.
我什么都穿不过去
Well, I can't phase anything.
我都没法让自己穿越物体  更别说还有重力
I can't even phase myself, let alone at G-Force.
等等  重力  就是这个
Wait, G-For-- G-Force, that's it.
飞机还在上升
The plane is still ascending.
一旦他炸掉另一个引擎
Once he blows up the other engine,
飞机在开始下降之前
it's gonna slow down and point downwards
会减速并使机头向下
before it starts its descent.
飞机会有十秒钟处于失重状态
That'll give us about ten seconds of zero Gs on the plane.
-没错  -失重意味着没有动能
- Yeah. - And zero Gs means no kinetic energy,
也就是说路霸没有超能力
means Gridlock has no powers.
你能用缺口把他们传送到飞机上吗
Can you breach them onto the plane?
飞机的速度太快了
A plane goes way too fast.
我得亲眼看到它
I'd need to see it in person.
-那就快去  -但是我没有战衣
- Then go. - But I don't have a suit.
事实上  我有备用的
I actually have a backup.
我从博物馆拿到的不仅有超能力者名单
I got more than just a list of metas from that museum.
天哪  吉娜  这是我做的吗
Damn, Gina. I made that?
其实是蔡瑞安做的
Uh, Ryan Choi, actually.
这可是一套超级战衣
Oh, this is a supersuit.
-无意冒犯  -没关系
- No offense. - None taken.
引擎
各位  他刚刚毁掉了另一个引擎
Guys, he just took out the other engine.
你能做到
You can do this.
酒后震波可不好  我感觉快要吐了
Don't drink and vibe. I feel like I'm gonna hurl.
飞机在减速
It's slowing.
各位  你们有十秒钟时间
Guys, you've got ten seconds.
十
Ten.
九
Nine.
八
Eight.
七
Seven.
六
Six.
五
Five.
四
Four.
三
Three.
二
Two.
一
One.
大家保持冷静  好吗
Okay, everybody stay calm, all right?
冷静
Just stay calm.
来吧
All right, come on.
各自负责一面机身
Hey, take a wall, all right?
我们能做到
We got this.
巴里  快点
Barry, hurry.
-不起作用  -什么
- It's not working. - What?
我做不到
I can't do this.
好吧  听着  深呼吸
All right, yes-- listen to me, just breathe.
感受脚下的地板
Feel the floor beneath your feet.
感受飞机的声音
Feel the rumble of the plane.
感受空气
Feel the air.
感受吹到你脸上的风
Feel that wind on your face,
-还有闪电  -还有闪电
- and the lightning. - And the lightning.
感受电流在你的血管里穿梭
Feel its electricity pumping through your veins,
流过你身体中的每一处神经
traveling to every nerve in your body
就像你永远不想停止的触电一样
like a shock you never want to end.
-你不再是你自己了  -你不再是你自己了
- You are no longer you now. - You're no longer you.
你融入了更宏大的存在
You're part of something greater.
融入了神速力
Part of the Speed Force.
没错
That's right.
好了  它是我们的
All right, it's ours.
现在去做吧
Now, let's do it.
大家坐稳
Everybody hold on!
坐稳
Hold on!
你还好吗
Are you okay?
干得漂亮
Nice.
你穿过来了
You phased.
第一次
For the first time!
路霸将被押送至铁山监狱的超能力区
Well, Gridlock's off to Iron Heights' meta wing.
突发新闻  超能力劫匪被逮捕
他会在那里呆上很长一段时间
Where he won't be moving from for a very long time.
多亏了你的帮忙
Thanks to your help.
很高兴我们能组队
I'm glad we got to team up.
我也是
Me too.
女士们
Ladies and gentleman,
向超光速粒子吸收增强器2.5版本打个招呼
say hello to the tachyon absorption enhancer 2.5,
已经重新调试完成了
now complete with completely recalibrated
时间调查局的技术
Time Bureau technology.
我们还没有进行测试  但它应该能够
We haven't tested it yet, but it should counterbalance
平衡诺拉细胞中的负超光速粒子
the negative tachyons in Nora's cells.
给你  比利·皮尔格林
Here you go, Billy Pilgrim.
你不会困在时间里了
Consider yourself unstuck in time.
所以现在我可以跑回家了
So I can run home now?
或者...
Or...
也许我们可以缓一缓
maybe we hit pause on this thing.
你想让诺拉留下
You want Nora to stay?
我以为送她回家是我们的首要任务
Um, yeah, I thought getting her home was our priority.
是的  我只是...
No, it is, I just--
现在我想也许我们应该确保
now, I'm thinking that maybe we should make sure
她的超能力都正常
her powers are working correctly
再送她回家
before we send her home.
时间线怎么办
And what about the timeline?
是有风险  我不知道
It's risky, but I don't know.
沃利和我想了一下
I mean, Wally and I were talking about it.
传奇们有个理论
Yeah, the Legends have a theory.
有些历史事件是有弹性的
Uh, there are some historical events that are soft.
基本上  你改变那些
Basically, you change those,
不会有什么影响
it's not going to affect much else,
比如说没及时抓住路霸
like catching Gridlock late.
有些是固定的
And then, there are those that are fixed.
扰乱它们  会有各种各样疯狂的事情发生
You mess with them, and all sorts of craziness starts to happen.
比如说我妈妈死的那晚
Like the night my mom died.
改变它会产生闪点
Changing that created Flashpoint.
看来诺拉需要一个地方住下
It looks like Nora is gonna need a place to stay.
是的  我会呆在休息室
Uh, yes, and I'll stay in the lounge.
什么休息室
What lounge?
这个休息室
This lounge.
-该死  -爸
- Damn. - Dad.
-你找到了我的据点  -你知道这地方
- You found my spot. - You knew about this?
从第一天起我就在这打盹了
I've been napping in here since day one.
诺拉会住在这里
Uh, well, Nora was gonna stay here,
如果你不介意的话
if that's all right with you.
好
Okay, well,
现在我可以了解我的外孙女了
now I can get to know my granddaughter.
打扰一下  你见到了猫王
I'm sorry, you met Elvis?
见到他
Met him?
沃利叔叔打败了他的孪生兄弟鬼魂
Uncle Wally fought the ghost of his twin brother.
我去了寺院
I, uh--I went to a monastery,
我正试图找到自己
and I was trying to find myself,
就快要找到了
but I was really close.
然后传奇们来了  一下子把我带走了
Then, the Legends came, they swooped me up,
之后生活变得更加疯狂
and life got even more crazy.
你想要回去  不是吗
You want to go back, don't you?
不行  我刚回来
I can't. I mean, I just got here.
我不想离开小队  我不想离开你
I don't want to leave the team. I don't want to leave you.
沃利  这个房间的所有人都爱你  特别是我
Wally, everybody in this room loves you, especially me.
但你没有完成你要做的事情
But you didn't finish what you set out to do,
没有人会拦着你
and nobody's gonna get in your way.
向我保证  当你找到你寻找的东西
So promise me, when you find what you're looking for,
再回来  不然你就会
come back, or you're gonna have
在你的禅修花园里发现一个生气老爸
a very angry-looking dad in your zen garden.
你会照顾他吧  XS
Will you take care of him, XS?
没问题  闪电小子
You got it, Kid Flash.
你还好吗
You okay?
还好
Yeah.
我以为我错过了和诺拉建立联系的机会
I thought I missed out on my chance to connect with Nora,
但现在她要留下  我还有机会
but now that she's staying, I get another shot.
如果你在飞机上看到了她
If you could have seen her on that plane,
你会知道你们已经有了联系
you'd know that you guys are already connected.
是吗
Really?
她很无畏  和你一样
She was fearless, just like you.
-我们有一个女儿  -是的
- We have a daughter together. - Yeah.
我们造了一个人
We make a person.
最后  所有事情都能解决
In the end, everything works out.
我们有幸福的结局
We get our happy ending.
如果巴里可以回到过去
If Barry can go back in time,
为什么他不阻止思考者杀掉我
why didn't he stop the Thinker from killing me?
我开玩笑的
Kidding, I'm kidding.
各位  我开玩笑的
Guys, I'm kidding.
我知道这会打破
I realize that could have upset
宇宙微妙的平衡
the delicate balance of the universe.
再说  如果他这么做了  谁知道
Besides, if he did that, who knows?
他也许会创造一条时间线
He might have created a timeline where
我在粒子加速器爆炸时就死了
I died in that particle accelerator explosion.
这样倒好了
Wishful thinking.
开玩笑的  我很高兴你在这里
Kidding. I'm glad you're here,
而且我很高兴我们不用手把手
and I'm glad that we don't have to hold your hand
解释穿越的事情  你快想明白了
through the time travel thing; you're figuring it out.
是的  穿越不是我唯一解决的谜团
Yeah, well, time travel's not the only mystery I solved.
当你们在和路霸战斗时
While you guys were fighting Gridlock,
我在查这些
I was, uh, running this down.
-这是什么  -答案
- What's this? - An answer.
和更多问题
And a lot more questions.
这是我父亲的死亡证明
It's my father's death certificate.
我县里的一个朋友帮了忙
A friend at county helped me out with that.
签署的法医  卡梅伦·马肯特
The ME who signed off on it, Cameron Mahkent?
并不存在
He doesn't exist.
那么  这份死亡证明
So then, this death certificate...
是假的
Is a fake.
你应该休息一下  今天够累了
You should get some rest. You've had a long day.
我试试吧
Ooh, I'll try.
我太激动了  真的
I'm just so excited. Like, literally.
穿越激发了我体内所有的电子云
Phasing excited all of the electron clouds in my body.
如果你不累
Well, if you're not tired,
两个曲奇冰淇淋球听起来不错
two scoops of cookie dough ice cream sound good right now.
欢乐港的吗
From Happy Harbor?
如果你不介意
If that's okay with you.
没问题
It is, yeah.
给我带回来些薄荷片
Just, uh, bring me back some mint chip.
我叫诺拉·韦斯特·艾伦
My name is Nora West Allen,
我是世界上最快的女人
and I'm the fastest woman alive.
我小的时候  我父亲消失在
When I was a child, my father disappeared
难以想象的事物中
in something impossible.
之后我长大成为了奇迹
Then I grew up and became the impossible.
现在我正努力不辜负他创造的遗泽
Now I'm trying to live up to the legacy he created
直到有一天  我会阻止他的消失
so that one day, I'll stop him from ever disappearing.
我是XS
I'm XS.
多么酷炫
How schway is that?
中城警局  不许动
CCPD! Stay where you are.
站住  不许动
Freeze, don't move.
你是谁
Who the hell are you?
你想要什么
Wh--what do you want?
你们所有人去死
For all of you to die.